Nikita Rozhkov

ronikita98.07@gmail.com | +37455988952 | Linkedin

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Senior Software Engineer with more than 6 years of experience. I have deep knowledge in the field of architecture design, finding solutions to complex problems, integrating new solutions into existing functionality, data processing and web API development. Now I work for an advanced biotechnology company, and I am responsible for developing a semi-automatic reporting system for each patient and integrating the system with other company services. Since I joined the company, the report build speed has increased 10 times, and the number of users of our service has increased 7 times. Proficient in Python, FastAPI, Flask, PostgreSQL, Elasticsearch, Celery, Redis, asyncio, aiohttp, Kubernetes, AWS, Docker, AirFlow, NLP, Git, Agile and Jira.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

BostonGene

Pioneering biomedical Software company

2022 - pres Senior Software Engineer

Responsible for implementation of service architecture using Flask, Fast API and infrastructure development.

- Developed a new service architecture, which resulted in a 30% increase in report build speed and simplified the implementation of new features
- Mentored and led the developer's team of 5 people
- Increased the accuracy of automatic detection of relevant clinical trials by 80%
- Infrastructure development

2021-2022 Middle Software Engineer

- Accelerated the assembly of reports by 3 times
- Utilized databases as PostgreSQL and Elasticsearch

2020-2021 Junior Software Engineer

- Provided technical support to end-users
- Authored unit, integration, smoke and e2e tests via pytest

2019 - 2020 Lomonosov Moscow State University

Top public university in Russia

Reseacher

Responsible for exploring the possibility of combining classical word processing and machine learning techniques.

- Developed own method of identifying general scientific stable phrases
- Achieved 96% accuracy on the test sample and 89% on raw data
- Based on the results of the work, a report was prepared for the Lomonosov conference

2018 - 2019

Consultant Plus

Top legal reference system

Software Engineer Intern

Responsible for development of a web application for obtaining information about a counterparty.

• Developed from scratch a system for evaluating a counterparty

EDUCATION

2020-2022 Lomonosov Moscow State University (MSU) | Master's Degree, Artificial Intelligence | GPA 3.67

2016-2020 Lomonosov Moscow State University (MSU) | Bachelor's Degree, Computer Science | GPA 3.04

SKILLS

Python • Git • Flask • FastAPI • Microservices • API Development • Technical Support • Celery • Redis • PostgreSQL • SQLAlchemy • Elasticsearch • Concourse CI • Kubernetes • AWS • Docker • AirFlow • Jira • Agile • Architecture design • SOLID principles • Design Patterns • DDD • EDD • TDD • Natural Language Processing (NLP) • Pytest • Alembic • asyncio • aiohttp